[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon and welcome to
&gt;&gt; 下午好 欢迎参加
what's new in testing.
“测试新内容”会议
My name is Wil and I work on
我叫 Wil 从事
Xcode and on XCTest.
Xcode 和 XCTest 方面的工作
So, what is new in testing?
那么 有哪些关于测试的新内容呢
The answer is a lot.
答案是有很多
In fact, so much that we don't
实际上 由于数量太多 我们
have time to do all of the
没时间在今天
justice here today, so let's get
逐一介绍
started.
那就开始吧
First off, we have a bunch of
首先 我们对 Xcode 8.3
enhancements in both Xcode 8.3
和 Xcode 9 都进行了一系列的
and Xcode 9.
改进
I'm going to just call these out
我想先把这些改进列举出来
and then I'm going to let you
然后再让你
read up on them in the reference
在 XCTest 的参考文档中
documentation for XCTest which
详细了解 这份文档
has just gotten a major
刚进行了大幅度
overhaul.
更新
Then we'll take a look at new
之后我们会了解一下
APIs for asynchronous testing
用于异步测试的新 API
followed by multi-app testing
多 App 测试
and some great performance
以及 UI 测试的
improvements in UI testing.
重要性能改进
Finally, we'll wrap things up
最后 我们会以一组
with a group of technologies
叫做 Activity 附件
called activities, attachments,
和屏幕快照的技术
and screenshots.
来收尾
Let's look at those
让我们来看一看
enhancements.
这些改进
So, in Xcode 8.3, we added UI
对于 Xcode 8.3 我们在针对 Siri 意图的
testing for Siri intents with
UI 测试中添加了
the new XCUISiriService.
新的 XCUISiriService
We also introduced UI testing
同时 我们在 macOS
support for the Touch Bar on
的 Touch Bar 中增加了
macOS.
UI 测试支持
In XCTest for Xcode 9 we have
在 Xcode 9 的 XCTest 中 我们
refined the framework Swift
改良了 Swift 接口框架
interface as part of the Swift 4
作为 Swift 4 的一部分
effort and we've also added a
我们还增加了一个
new block-based teardown API
新的基于块的 Teardown API
that lets you structure context
能够在测试方法中构建
specific teardown in your test
上下文特定的 Teardown
methods without additional state
而无需测试类别的
or properties in your test
额外状态或
classes.
属性
In UI testing we've introduced a
在 UI 测试中 我们为 macOS
new element type for the macOS
的菜单项推出了
menu bar items.
新的元素类别
In addition, there's new API on
此外 XCUI 元素中
XCUI element that waits on the
有新的针对
existence of an element reducing
XCUIElement 的 API
the need for sleep or other
从而减少对 sleep() 函数的需求或
artificial delays in your tests.
测试中其他人工延迟
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Xcodebuild now launches tests
现在 xcodebuild 命令支持直接通过
directly via core simulator so
CoreSimulator 启动测试
you'll no longer see the
这样你在命令行
simulator app launch when
运行测试时 就不再会
running tests from the command
看到模拟器 App
line.
启动了
We're also very excited to
同时 我们也很高兴地
announce Xcodebuild now supports
宣布 xcodebuild 命令现在支持
parallel device testing.
并行设备测试了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
This means if you pass multiple
这意味着如果你传递
destination specifiers to
多个目标区分符到
Xcodebuild it will build once
xcodebuild 命令那么就可以使用一个平台
for all specifiers sharing the
一次性创建
same platform and then run the
所有区分符 然后
test for those destinations
为这些目标同时
simultaneously.
运行测试
This should give a huge speedup
这会极大地提高
to many continuous integration
许多持续集成情景
scenarios.
的速度
On the localization side, in
在本地化方面
Xcode 9 you can set the language
你可以在 Xcode 9 中设定运行测试
and region for your test to run
所使用的语言
in.
和区域
This scheme option allows you to
这个 Scheme 选项可以让你
easily test many different
轻松测试你项目的
localizations for your projects.
各种本地化内容
I also want to take a moment to
我还想花些时间来
call your attention to some
请大家看一看
improvements in Xcode Server.
Xcode Server 的改进
So first of all, as of Xcode 9
首先 有了 Xcode 9
you no longer need macOS server,
就不再需要 macOS 服务器了
you can turn on Xcode Server for
你的团队可以直接在 Xcode 的
your team with just the flick of
全新偏好面板
a switch by going to the new
拨一下开关
preferences pane directly in
即可开启
Xcode.
Xcode Server
Xcode Server also has an
Xcode Server 也具有
improved provisioning workflow
经过优化的配置工作流
and adopts the Xcodebuild
并在 CoreSimulator 和
improvements for CoreSimulator
并行测试中采用了
and parallel testing.
改进后的 xcodebuild 命令
And those per scheme
同时 每个 Scheme 的
localization support
本地化支持
automatically extends to all of
会自动覆盖到
your bots.
你所有的机器人
So that is our whirlwind tour of
那么以上就是我们最令人激动的
the most exciting new
全新改进
enhancements.
的快速概览
Now let's slow down a bit and
现在 让我们放慢速度
take a closer look at
来仔细看看
asynchronous testing.
异步测试
Async testing allows you to
异步测试能够
validate code which doesn't
验证没有
finish immediately, but instead
立即完成
calls back later with closures,
但随后却回调
delegate methods or other
闭包 委托方法或其他
delayed completions.
延迟完成的代码
This includes tasks like opening
这其中含有的任务包括打开文档
documents, work done on
后台线程完成
background threads,
的工作
communicating with other
以及与其他进程
processes, network activity,
网络 Activity
animations, and a range of UI
动画及一系列
testing scenarios.
UI 测试情景进行的通信
We introduced APIs for async
几年前 我们
testing in Xcode 6 several years
在 Xcode 6 的异步测试中
ago now.
推出了API
These methods on XCTestCase let
这些 XCTestCase 上的方法
you define conditions or
可以让你定义
expectations as we call them and
调用时的条件或期望
then have your test wait for
然后再让测试等待
them to complete or be
这些条件或期望
fulfilled.
完成或满足
So, here's a simple example.
这里是一个简单的例子
This fragment of test code opens
这个测试代码的片段
a document, waits for it to
打开了文档 等着它
finish, and asserts that it was
完成并假设它已经
successful.
成功了
The expectation object is
期望对象
created before the document is
在文档打开之前就已经
opened.
创建了
The test waits for it below the
测试等待该文档在
call to open and fulfills it
调用下打开并
inside the closure which allows
在闭包中完成 这使得
the test to then continue on and
测试继续运行
execute the test code after the
并在等待调用后
call to wait.
执行测试代码
But this is the original API
但这是我们在 Xcode 6 里
that we had in Xcode 6.
的初始 API
It works well enough, but it has
它的性能已经足够好了
some limitations.
但仍存在一些限制
First, timeout string waiting
首先 等待 Timeout String
are always treated as test
总是被当成
failures.
测试失败来对待
Second, waiting requires the
其次 等待需要
test object itself which makes
测试对象本身
it hard to factor out into any
这让提取任何类别的
kind of test library or support
测试库或
code.
支持代码变得很困难
It's also not possible to have
我们所称的嵌套等待
what we call nested waiting.
在这个 API 中也同样不可能
Nested waiting involves
嵌套等待涉及到
additional groups of
需要在外部权重
expectations that get waited on
上下文内等待的
inside an outer weight context.
额外期望群组
To solve these problems, we've
为了解决这些问题 我们
introduced a new class
推出了新一类
XCTWaiter.
XCTWaiter
This class extracts the logic of
这一类提取了过去
waiting that used to be
XCTestCase 中含有的
contained in XCTestCase and
等待逻辑
allows you to explicitly declare
并允许你明确声明
the expectations you're waiting
正在等待的
on.
期望
Timeouts and other events are
超时和其他事件可
handled through a delegate API
通过一个委托 API 进行处理
and are also returned from the
并且会从等待 API 中
wait API as a result value.
作为结果值返回
This provides considerably more
这就为构建异步测试
flexibility in how you can
提供了
structure your asynchronous
更多的
tests.
灵活性
If we return to the previous
如果我们回到上一个
example, let's take a look at
例子 让我们来看一看
what the options are now for
现在等待有哪些
waiting.
选项
In the original code, note that
在初始代码中 我们注意到
no expectations are mentioned.
并未提到任何期望
This is because the
这是因为
implementation is implicit, it
执行是隐式的
waits on all active expectations
它等待着测试对象
the test object has created.
创建的所有活跃期望
With just a small change now the
而现在 只需要稍微改变
test is waiting explicitly on
测试便可实现对文档期望的
the document expectation.
显式等待
Now another equivalent way of
构建这个的一个
constructing this is to create
等价的方式是创建
an instance of XCTWaiter with a
XCTWaiter 的一个实例
test case as delegate.
并将测试作为托管
And yet another option is to
还有另一个选择是
wait using a class method on
采用 XCTWaiter 类方法
XCTWaiter and then handle the
进行等待 然后再处理
result value.
结果值
This flexibility makes it really
这一灵活性使得
easy to use XCTWaiter in helper
在 Helper 方法 嵌套上下文
method, nested contexts or in
或在从测试用例中
test library code that's
完全解耦的
completely decoupled from your
测试库代码上使用 XCTWaiter
test cases.
变得十分容易
Now in addition, to creating
除此之外 为了创建
XCTWaiter we've also expanded
XCTWaiter 我们同时也扩充了
the API for XCTTestExpectation.
XCTTestExpectation 的 API
The initializer is now public
目前 初始化程序
API which also decouples the
已经在公开的 API 中提供
creation of expectations from
它也从 XCTestCase 中解耦
XCTestCase.
期望的创建
We've also introduced an
我们还引入了
expected fulfillment count
期望实现数
property, this is where
属性 在这一属性下
expectations representing
期望象征着
conditions which occur multiple
多次出现的
times.
条件
Now for conditions which should
对于那些根本不该出现的
not occur at all there's an
条件 有一个
inverted API for expectations
针对期望的倒置 API
which will cause the waiter to
这会让 XCTWaiter
raise a failure only if the
只在超时崩溃前
expectation is fulfilled before
就达到期望的时候
the timeout collapses.
才报告错误
Finally, XCTWaiter allows you to
最后 XCTWaiter 可以
enforce the order in which
加强期望实现
expectations are fulfilled using
的命令 这是通过利用
an optional flag with the wait
等待 API 的可选旗标
APIs.
实现的
So, those are the updates to
以上 便是异步测试
asynchronous testing, XCTWaiter,
XCTWaiter 和我们用于管理期望
our new API for managing
的新 API 的进展情况
expectations and a bunch of
以及一系列
improvements to XCTest
XCTest 期望的
expectation.
改进情况
Both of these classes are fully
这些类均与 XCTestCase
decoupled from XCTestCase giving
完全解耦并提供了
you a much easier and more
一个更便捷和
powerful system to use.
更强大的系统供大家使用
Now I'd like to talk about UI
下面 我想介绍一下 UI
testing and in particular, UI
测试 尤其是
testing with multiple
使用多应用程序的
applications.
UI 测试
The starting point of almost
几乎所有 UI 测试
every UI test is an
的起始点都是
XCUIApplication instance.
XCUIApplication 实例
This class lets you launch and
这一类别可以让你启动并
terminate the app you're
中断正在测试的 App
testing, as well as create
同时创建
queries for finding the user
查询命令以找到用户
interface elements which you
接口元素 而后再通过
then automate by sending
发送综合事件
synthetic events.
使其自动化
UI testing has a target
UI 测试有一个目标
application concept which is the
应用程序概念 也就是指
application your tests are
主要测试的那个
primarily testing.
应用程序
In your project settings for
在测试的工程设置中
your tests you designate an app
你可以指定相同工程中的
in the same project as being the
一个应用程序作为
target application.
目标应用程序
This enables you to call the
这就让你可以调用
default initializer for
XCUIApplication 的
XCUIApplication and the instance
默认初始化程序并创建
will be created with the
带有安装
information for installing,
启动和与该应用程序
launching and interacting with
交互等信息的
that application.
实例
This mechanism is very
这一机制十分
convenient, but it doesn't give
便捷 但却不能用于
you a way to test other
测试其他的
applications.
应用程序
Some examples of what we would
其他被我们称作
call multi-app scenarios include
多应用程序情景的例子包括
app groups where you have more
App 群组 即一个工程中
than one application in your
存在不止一个应用程序
project and they somehow
并且它们
interact together and pass data
进行交互并
back and forth.
传递数据
Another example would be
另一个例子则是
settings if you need to automate
设置 如果你需要将应用程序
the settings for your app and
的设置自动化并
change preferences for different
改变不同测试情景的
test scenarios.
偏好
And yet another example, our app
还有另一个例子 即应用程序
extensions.
扩展
All of these require more than a
全部应用程序的扩展所需要的不止是
single target application.
单一的目标应用程序
To solve this, we've added some
为了解决这一问题 我们在
new APIs to XCUIApplication.
XCUIApplication 中添加了新的 API
First, there are initializers
首先 我们有初始化程序
that allow you to specify an app
让你可以通过 Bundle ID
by its bundle ID or
来指定 App 或
alternatively on macOS you can
也可以在 macOS 中
also use a file URL to designate
利用文件 URL 来指定
the location of the app on disk.
磁盘中 App 的位置
Second, we've added an activate
其次 我们添加了一个 active() 方法
method that will bring the app
将应用程序
from the background to the
从后台拉到前台
foreground if it's already
前提是应用程序已经
running and launch a new
在运行 如果没有运行 则将启动
instance if it's not.
新的实例
But launch API would terminate
但启动 API 将首先中断
any previous running instance
任何之前的运行实例
first, so you always have a
因此你在开始
cleaner slate when you start
测试时总是需要
your test.
从头开始
Activate is useful for those
active() 方法很有用 尤其是
scenarios when you're not
在那些你
interested in wiping out
没兴趣清除
previous state, but you actually
此前的状态 但实际上
want to resume from some earlier
又想在测试的更早期
point in the test.
重新开始的情景中
Finally, there's a new state
最后 还有一个新的状态
property that you can use to
属性可以用来
monitor changes in the
监控正在测试的
applications you're testing.
应用程序中的变化
So, here's some example of using
那么下面就举几个使用这些 API 的
these APIs.
例子
This code creates two
这一代码使用 Bundle ID
XCUIApplication instances with
创建了两个
bundle IDs.
XCUIApplication 实例
This is a pair of apps perhaps
这可能是一个 App 群组里的
in an app group.
一对应用程序
After launching and interacting
在启动和交互
the readerApp the test then
readerApp 后 测试接下来
launches the writerApp and
启动了 writerApp
finally, after some more
最后 在进行了更多的
interaction it uses the activate
交互后 应用程序使用 Activate
API to bring the readerApp back
API 将 readerApp 拉回
to the foreground without
前台而没有
terminating it first.
在一开始就将之中断
So now let's see that in action,
下面我们来看一看实际操作
here's Warren Ma with a demo of
有请 Warren Ma 为我们进行
multi-app UI testing.
多应用程序 UI 测试的 Demo
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Wil.
谢谢你 Wil
So as Wil just described, now in
正如威尔刚才描述的那样
Xcode 9 you can write UI tests
现在在 Xcode 9 中 你可以编写
that involve multiple
涉及多个应用程序的
applications and I'm excited to
UI 测试 我很高兴
show you guys how you might
向大家展示如何
incorporate the new APIs into
将新的 API 纳入
your own test suites.
自己的测试集中
So, let me go ahead and start by
那么 下面我想先给大家
showing you these two related
展示一下我这里的
apps that I have here.
两个关联 App
I'm running them on a
我现在是在一个开发设备上
development device and I'm using
运行这些程序
QuickTime to show you what's on
我在使用 QuickTime 来向大家展示
the screen.
屏幕上的内容
The first one is a message
第一个是一个信息
posting app, the writerApp.
发送 App  叫做 writerApp
Here we have a username, we have
这里我们有一个用户名 我们还有
a text view that we can tap
一个可以输入的文本视图
into, we can type out a test
我们可以输入一条测试
message, tap return on the
信息 点击键盘上的
keyboard and post it to the
Return 键 并通过“Send（发送）”按钮
server by tapping on the Send
将信息发布在
button.
服务器上
Great, so it's been posted.
很好 现在信息已经发布了
Now how do we view these
那么现在我们要怎样来浏览这些
messages?
信息呢
Well that's the purpose of our
这就是我们第二个 App
second app the readerApp.
readerApp 的任务了
Here is a list of all messages
这里列出了所有
that have been posted to the
发布在服务器上的
server and at the very top is
信息 而最上面的一条
the most recent message posted
是最新发布的信息
the one I just sent and we can
也就是我刚刚发布的信息 我们可以
tap into that to view it in
点击信息进行详细地
detail.
浏览
And then we can return to that
然后我们可以返回
list of messages using the
信息列表 通过
button at the top left All
左上角的“All Messages（所有信息）”
Messages.
按钮来返回
So, let's say you want to test
我们假设你想测试一下
this process of typing out a
这个过程 即在
test message in the writerApp,
writerApp 中输入文本信息
posing it to the server and then
发布在服务器上 然后再
verifying that it appears at the
从第二个应用程序中去
top of the list of messages from
验证信息是否出现在信息列表的
the second application.
第一条
Well before Xcode 9 you would
在 Xcode 9 之前 你不得不
have to write separate UI tests
为每个应用程序编写
for each application and even
不同的 UI 测试
then, you wouldn't really have a
那时甚至没有真正的方法
way of verifying the behavior
来验证这两者之间的
between both.
行为
But now with multi-app testing
但现在 有了 Xcode 9 的多 App 测试
in Xcode 9, multi-UI testing in
Xcode 9 的多 UI 测试
Xcode 9 we can easily test
我们可以轻松测试
real-world scenarios between
多个应用程序间的
multiple applications.
现实世界情景
To show you how that looks let's
为了给大家展示 我们来
write a quick UI test to
快速编写一个 UI 测试
automate the workflow I just
将我刚刚演示的这个工作流
demonstrated.
自动化
All right, the first step in our
好了 那我们测试的
test is to launch our Reader
第一步就是启动我们的阅读
application.
应用程序
In order to do that we're going
为了启动这一程序 我们需要
to initialize it using its
使用它的 Bundle ID
bundle ID.
进行初始化
Afterwards we can go ahead and
这一步之后 我们就可以继续并
launch it from a clean state.
重新启动程序
Once our readerApp has been
一旦我们启动了 readerApp
launched we're just going to go
我们就可以继续
ahead and verify the first
在信息列表中
message in that list of
验证第一条
messages.
信息
To do that we'll tap into the
要做到这一点 我们得点击
first message in the list, we'll
列表的第一条信息 我们
verify that its contents are
可以验证里面的内容
what we expect and finally,
是否是我们想看的那条 最后
we'll return to the list of
我们可以返回
messages using that button at
信息列表 利用左上角的
the top left.
按钮
Once we verified the first
一旦我们验证了
message in the list we want to
列表中的第一条信息 我们
type out our test message and
就可以输入文本信息并
post it to the server into the
通过 writerApp 来将信息发布在
writerApp.
服务器上
To do that the first step once
要做到这一点 第一步
again is to initialize the
还是使用 Bundle ID
writerApp using its bundle ID,
将 writerApp 初始化
in this case it's
在这个例子里 ID 是
com.mycompany.Writer.
com.mycompany.Writer
Afterwards, it's as easy as just
完成这些之后
calling Activate.
仅须调用 active() 方法就可以了
Now Activate also waits for the
现在 activate() 也要等待
application state to become
应用程序状态在
running foreground before
返回之前成为在前台
returning, so we don't need to
运行 因此我们不需要
do any sort of manual waiting on
对应用程序的状态进行任何
the application state.
手动等待
Once Activate has returned we
一旦 active() 返回了 我们就
know that the test is good to
知道测试进展良好
continue.
可以继续了
Once the writerApp is running
一旦 writerApp 在前台
foreground we can go ahead and
运行 我们就可以继续
compose our test message and
编写文本信息并
post it to the server.
发布在服务器上
To do that we'll tap into the
要做到这一点 我们要使用
text field, we'll type out our
文本框输入我们的
test message, we'll tap on the
文本信息 然后点击
return button on the keyboard,
键盘上的 Return 按钮
and then we'll tap on the send
再点击“Send（发送）”
button to post it to the server.
将信息发布到服务器
Now we want to make sure that it
现在 我们得确保信息
appears on the top of the list
出现在了 readerApp
of the messages in the
信息列表
readerApp.
的首条
Earlier we used Activate to
之前 我们使用了 active() 在
switch between the two
两个应用程序间
applications, but in this case,
转换 而在这个例子中
let's make use of that back to
让我们使用 iOS 系统
app button that's built into iOS
创建的返回应用程序按钮
which appears at the top left
这个按钮位于屏幕的
corner of the screen.
左上角
So, to do that we're going to
要做到这一点 我们需要
tap on the back to app button.
点击返回应用程序按钮
However, in this case because
但在这个例子中 由于
we're not using Activate we do
我们未使用 active()  因此我们
need to manually wait on the
需要手动等待
application state to become
应用程序状态在
running foreground before
前台运行 之后
continuing with the test.
才能继续测试
So, to do that let's make use of
而要做到这一点 我们得利用
the new predicate based
基于新 Predicate 的
expectation API.
期望 API
So, we want to make sure that
所以 我们得确保
the Reader app state has become
readerApp 的状态在返回
running foreground before
之前在前台
returning.
运行
After we've defined our
我们在定义了我们的
expectation we'll go ahead and
期望之后 可以继续下一步并
wait for that expectation to
等待这个期望
become true with a timeout of 10
在超时 10 秒后变为 True
seconds which should be more
这个时间应该是
than sufficient.
绰绰有余的
Once the Reader app has become
一旦 readerApp 开始在前台
running foreground we can go
运行 我们就可以
ahead and continue with the
继续完成
final step of our test which is
测试的最后一步 也就是
to verify that the message
验证信息是否出现
appears at the top of the list.
在列表的顶部
Similar to what we did before,
同我们刚刚所做的类似
we'll tape into the first
我们可以点击列表的
message in the list, we'll
第一条信息 然后验证
verify that its contents are the
信息的内容是否是
message that we just posted, and
我们刚刚发布的内容
then we'll return to the list of
然后再返回到
messages.
信息列表
So, let's go ahead and run the
下面就让我们实际操作一下
test to see it in action.
看看真实的测试
To do that I'll click on the
首先 我要点击
test diamond in the left-hand
左栏的
gutter.
测试方块
So, when you run UI tests in
这样 当一般情况下你运行
general it has to install what
UI 测试时 就需要安装
is called the UI test runner and
所谓的 UI 测试运行器并且
that is the test process in
那是除了安装应用
which UI tests run in addition
程序外 UI 测试运行的
to installing the app.
测试流程
So, it just takes a bit of time
所以 只需要一点点时间
for that to launch.
就可以启动了
Once it's launched the test can
一旦启动后 测试
go ahead and continue to run.
便可继续运行
So once again, the first step of
因此同之前一样 测试的
our test was to launch the
第一步是启动
Reader app and verify the first
readerApp 并验证
message in the list of messages.
信息列表中的第一条信息
Then we use Activate to open the
接下来 我们使用 active() 方法来打开
Writer app, type out our test
writerApp 输入我们的测试
message and post it to the
信息并发布在
server.
服务器上
And we use the back to app
然后我们使用返回 App
button to switch back to the
按钮来转回到
Reader app and verify that the
readerApp 并验证
message appeared at the top the
信息是否出现在了列表的
list.
顶部
So [inaudible] how easy it is to
所以说 利用
make use of the awesome new
这款适用于 Xcode 9 的
multi-UI testing APIs available
超棒多 UI 测试 API
in Xcode 9 to test multiple
来测试多个应用程序是
applications.
多么容易啊
And with that I'd like to hand
那么下面我就把舞台
it back to Wil.
交回给 Wil
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Warren, that's really
谢谢你 Warren 真是非常
great stuff.
精彩的介绍
With just a few additions the
仅仅是通过添加一些新功能
realm of UI testing
UI 测试这一领域
possibilities has gotten much
的可能性便得到了
broader.
极大的拓宽
The new initializers let you
这个新的初始化程序可以
test any application and the
测试任何应用程序 而且
Activate API means you can
Activate API 意味着你可以在
switch between multiple
多应用程序间
applications without restarting
切换而无需重启这些程序
them, multi-app UI testing.
实现多应用程序 UI 测试
So, let's switch gears and talk
下面 让我们转换一下思路
about performance in UI testing.
来谈谈 UI 测试的性能
At the heart of UI testing are
UI 测试的核心是
the user interface elements that
你的测试希望
your test will want to interact
交互的用户接口
with.
元素
These are the buttons, labels,
这些元素包括按钮 标签
table views, etcetera.
表格视图等等
The UI tests create queries to
UI 测试通过创建查询来
describe how elements are found.
描述各元素是如何被发现的
For example, here a button
例如 这个按钮元素
element has the query
有一个
app.navigationBars.buttons with
app.navigationBars.buttons 查询
the subscript of done.
注释为“Done”
That means that the element has
这就意味着该元素具有
the type of a button, the label
一个按钮的属性 标签
or title of done and can be
或 Done 的标题并且
found in a navigation bar.
能在导航栏中找到
So how do these queries work?
那么这些查询是怎么工作的呢
Queries use accessibility data,
查询利用辅助功能数据
the same semantic information
这与 VoiceOver 技术
used by VoiceOver technologies
是一个意思
as a kind of searchable
将之作为应用程序的
structure for the application.
可被搜索的架构
To evaluate a query the test
为了评估一个查询 测试
process requests what we call a
进程请求对现有数据
snapshot of the current data.
进行所谓的快照
This request is sent from the
这一请求是从测试进程
test process to the application
发送至应用程序的
so these are separate processes,
所以这些是单独的进程
we're using interprocess
在这里我们使用了
communication here.
进程间通讯
The request is sent from the
这一请求是从测试进程
test process to the application,
发送至应用程序
now the application captures the
现在 应用程序捕捉了
snapshot data, serializes it and
快照数据 进行了排序并
transmits it back to the test
将之传回到测试
process.
进程
Once the test process has
一旦测试进程
unpacked the data it can
解包了数据 便能
evaluate the query by searching
通过在快照中搜寻
through the snapshot.
来评估查询
Snapshotting works and because
快照是有用的 正是因为
of how it works it takes a
它的运行方式 快照可以
single atomic representation of
在一瞬间捕捉
the state of the UI at that
UI 状态的原子表征
moment, but it introduces some
但这也带来了一些
performance challenges.
性能方面的挑战
If we consider two axes of
如果我们考虑性能的
performance, time on one hand
两个坐标轴 一个是时间
and memory on the other,
另一个是内存
snapshots have potential
快照在这两方面都
problems with both.
存在潜在问题
Snapshots that take too long for
对于有数个 UI 元素
apps that have many UI elements,
的应用程序来说 快照花费的时间过长
for example tables with
例如 对于有着数千行和
thousands of rows, large
大型集合视图的
collection views these will
表格而言 这会
cause timeouts that in turn
导致超时并会
trigger test failures.
引发测试失败
If the snapshot data is too
如果快照数据太大
large memory pressure on the
那么这对系统的内存压力
system may also result in
可能会导致
processes being terminated.
进程遭到中断
So, these challenges led us to
这些挑战让我们想到了下面这个
the question of how can we
问题 即我们如何才能
improve snapshot performance.
改善快照的性能
And we came up with several
我们总结出来了好几种
approaches.
方式
First of all, we wanted to cut
首先 我们想要
down on the overhead of
降低传输各进程
transporting all this data
间所有数据
between processes.
的开销
To do that we implemented what
要做到这一点 我们执行了
we are calling remote queries.
所谓的远程查询
With remote queries, instead of
有了远程查询
the test process requesting the
测试进程便不用请求
snapshot it actually transmits
快照 实际上只用传送
the query itself, which is a
查询本身 而这
very small amount of data.
只涉及非常少量的数据
The app will still create a
应用程序仍会创建
snapshot, but instead of
快照 但将
transporting it anywhere it
不再把它传送到任意地方
simply evaluates the query right
而只是评估进程中的
there in process.
查询
And at the end, it sends back
在最后 应用程序仅
just the results, again a tiny
向测试进程传回结果
amount of data, to test process.
同样只涉及少量的数据
So how does all this perform?
那么这一切的性能怎么样呢
Well remote query performance
经发现 远程查询的性能
turned out to speed things up by
可以将速度提高
as much as 20% and reduce memory
20% 并将内存泄漏
spiking by about 30%.
减少 30%
Now this was a good start, but
这当然是一个良好的开端 但
it was nowhere near what we had
还远未达到我们脑海中
in mind to achieve.
想要实现的目标
So that brought us to our second
那么这时候 就该我们的第二个
optimization which is query
优化项出场了 即
analysis.
查询分析
Our goal here was to reduce the
我们的目标是减少
size of the snapshot itself, to
快照自身的大小
simply collect less data.
收集更少的数据
Snapshot uses a fixed set of
快照使用了一套固定的
accessibility attributes, but we
辅助功能属性 但我们认为通过
determined by analyzing your
分析你的查询
queries we could identify a
我们可以识别出
minimal set of attributes,
一套数量最少的属性
roughly half the full set for
几乎只占到了许多普通
many common queries, greatly
查询的一半 这极大
reducing the amount of data
减少了收集的
collected.
数据量
Other properties that you might
对于一些具体的元素
need for assertions afterwards
在后续的断言中可能会
could still be fetched on demand
需要的其他属性仍可以
for specific elements, but the
按需获取 但
snapshot itself will now be much
快照自身将更加
slimmer.
轻便
So, query analysis turned out to
所以结果发现 查询分析
be an even better performance
是性能更加卓越的
optimization, roughly 50% faster
优化项 在普通情况下
in the common cases and having a
速度可提升 50% 并且
memory high watermark around 35%
内存阈值可降低
lower.
约 35%
So things are looking pretty
所以情况看起来相当
good, but we wanted to step back
不错 但我们想后退一步
and see if by really getting
看一看如果
outside the box we could
跳出固化的思维 我们是否能够
reimagine the system in a way
重新构建一个系统 并
that would transform things.
带来事物的变革
That brought us to the idea of
这就让我们有了
eliminating snapshots entirely.
将快照完全清除的这个想法
So how could we do that,
那么我们该怎么来做呢
snapshots gave us this guarantee
快照给我们提供了
of an atomic representation of
UI 状态的
the state of the UI?
原子表征
Well it turns out because of the
经发现 这得益于
remote query infrastructure we
远程查询基础结构 我们
now have that just because we
现在具备这一功能仅仅是因为我们
were already running our query
已经在应用程序的
in the process of the
进程中运行
application.
查询
So, where traditional queries
所以 传统查询
work by examining the snapshot
通过仔细检查快照
data exhaustively we have
数据来运转 我们
introduced an API called first
推出了一个叫做 First Match
match that tells the query stop
的 API 这个 API 会在你找到了
as soon as you find the first
第一个匹配项之后立刻
thing that matches because many
停止查询 因为
times it's excessive to search
很多时候 检索所有的
all through the data to find
数据以便找到
every possible match because you
所有可能的匹配项费时过多
can specify elements with
你可以以一个能够
precision that really makes them
使不同元素独特的精准度来
unique.
加以区分
So, first match causes the query
所以 First Match 导致查询
to return early and you can add
提早返回 并且你可以把它添加到
it to any query that you already
已有的任意
have.
查询中
Here's an example where first
下面举个例子来看看 First Match
match has been added to a query
是怎么添加进我们刚刚
we looked at earlier.
看过的这个查询中
And if you imagine that the app
如果设想一下我们
we were testing was one with a
正在测试的应用程序是一个带有
navigation bar and a table view
导航栏 表格视图
and the table had thousands of
和数千行表格
rows in it, traditional
的程序 传统的
evaluation would've examined
评估会依依检查
every single row in the table
表格中的每一行
even though we're looking for a
尽管我们要找的
button in the navigation bar.
是导航栏的一个按钮
But first match allows us to
但 First Match 则让我们可以
stop as soon as we find that
在找到那个按钮后立刻
button and we never look at a
停止 并且我们不需要检查
single row in that table.
表格中的每一行
So how does first match perform?
那么 First Match 的性能如何呢
Well it's safe to say first
可以说 First Match
match is a game changer.
改变了游戏规则
For many queries, it's as much
对于很多查询 几乎达到了
as an order of magnitude faster
一个数量级的提速
and eliminates memory spiking
并且还完全清除了内存
entirely.
泄漏
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Now the performance improvements
如今 First Match 的
in first match are fantastic,
性能提升非常显著
but it is important to notice
但重要的是要注意到
the difference between
传统查询之间的
traditional queries and not
差异 且不要
simply litter first match
不加考虑便
throughout your code without
将 First Match 胡乱运用于
some consideration.
整个代码中
Traditional query evaluation
传统的查询评估
finds all matches, this helps
会找出所有的匹配项 这能够
detect ambiguous queries because
帮助检测模糊查询 因为
will raise a failure if you
如果你尝试与存在
attempt to interact with an
多个匹配项的元素进行交互
element that has multiple
那么就会造成
matches.
失败
First match is removing that
First Match 消除了
protection, your test will get
这一层保护 你的测试只会获得
the first match.
第一个匹配项
And if something in your app's
如果应用程序的 UI
UI has changed so that query is
发生了变化 那么那个查询
actually not particularly
实际上便不够
precise and results would be a
精确 结果则是
non-unique result first match
非唯一结果
won't protect you and the
First Match 便不会提供保护
results could be surprising.
并且结果会让人意外
So, let's take a look at some
下面让我们来看看一些
example queries and consider
示例查询并思考
whether they're good candidates
它们是否适合进行
for first match.
First Match
So app.buttons.firstMatch is not
app.buttons.firstMatch 不是一个
a good idea, this is like going
好的选择 这就像
into the grocery store and just
走进一家杂货店 但只和老板说
saying I want food.
“我想要买点吃的”
You might get a frozen chicken
你可能买到冷冻的鸡肉
or a piece of bubblegum or
或是一块泡泡糖
banana there's no telling right.
又或是香蕉 这都说不准
So, this kind of query is simply
所以 这一类的查询
not precise enough for first
对于 First Match 来说
match.
还不够精准
Now this is a little better
现在则稍好了一点
because we've added an
因为我们在里面
identifying string to it as
添加了一个标识
well.
字符串
So many apps this might be
有这么多的应用程序 可能
sufficient right there.
对目前来说是足够的
But taking it a step further and
但如果再向进一步并且
adding more precision, more
为查询增加更多的精准度和
level of detail to the query
更多的细节
makes it a better candidate for
就使其能够更适合进行
first match and more likely to
First Match 并更有可能
just be robust everywhere while
在任何地方都保持稳定
still giving you the performance
同时仍然具备 First Match
improvements that come with
带有的性能
first match.
提升
So while talking about all these
因此在谈论所有这些
optimizations we need to tell
优化项时 我们需要给大家
you a little bit about
稍微介绍一下
block-based NSPredicates and
基于块的 NSPredicates 以及
using them in your queries.
如何在查询中进行使用
Unfortunately, they are at odds
不幸的是 它们同这些
with these optimizations, they
优化项并不兼容 它们
effectively inhibit them.
有效禁止了这些优化项
That is because first of all,
这是因为 首先
blocks can't be serialized, you
块无法被序列化
can't pass them around between
也无法在进程间传递
processes so that means no
这就意味着不存在
remote query and no first match.
远程查询和 First Match
The other problem is that we
另一个问题是我们
can't introspect, we can't look
无法内省 我们无法在运行时
into a block at runtime and no
查看块并知道
which attributes your query
查询实际需要的是
actually needs.
哪些属性
So that means the reduced
这就意味着当你正在使用
snapshot performance
基于块的 NSPredicates 时
improvements are also off the
快照性能的
table when you're using
提升也同样
block-based NSPredicates.
与此无关
Fortunately, the use of
幸运的是
block-based NSPredicates in UI
测试查询中使用基于
testing queries is relatively
块的 NSPredicates 相对
rare and can almost always be
少见 并且几乎始终可以
replaced with a format string or
与格式字符串或
an NSExpression based predicate
基于 NSExpression 的
instead.
Predicate 互换
Now if you find yourself with a
现在 如果你发现自己遇到
case that does require a
某个情况 即的确需要基于块的
block-based predicate, I mean
Predicate 我的意思是
they're still supported, they
它们仍然得到支持 它们
still work or even something
仍在运转或甚至
where it's much more convenient
使用其中之一会
to use one.
更加便捷
We'd like to know about it, we'd
我们想要去了解它 我们
like you to file a bug so that
希望你可以提交 Bug 这样
we can give you an API that does
我们就可以给你提供一个
the same thing, but in a way
处理相同任务的 API 但其处理方式
that works well with the query
能够与查询优化项
optimization.
兼容
So, we'd like to hear from you
所以 如果你觉得
if you feel you have cases where
手头有某些情况需要基于块的
you need a block-based
Predicate 我们很想听听你的
predicate.
看法
That wraps up our discussion of
以上就是我们对
UI testing performance
UI 测试性能提升的
improvements.
探讨
Queries should be all around
Xcode 9 中的查询整体来说
faster in Xcode 9.
应该更快
Some of the improvements, the
其中一些提升项 例如
remote query and first match do
远程查询和 First Match
also require the newest OS as
同样需要最新版的操作系统 比如
the newest macOS, iOS and tvOS.
最新的 macOS iOS 以及 Apple TVOS
But the query analysis benefits
但查询分析的益处即使是在
should work even on older OS's.
旧版的操作系统上也可以体现
So, UI testing performance we've
所以 在 UI 测试性能上 我们
done a lot of work here and we
做了很多工作并且我们
look forward to seeing your
也期待看到大家的
tests running faster.
测试运行地更加迅速
So finally, I'd like to share
所以最后 我想再跟大家
with you a new group of
分享一个新的
technologists called activities,
技术群组叫作
attachments and screenshots.
Activity 附件与屏幕快照
So, let's start with activities
下面 让我们先来看看 Activity
which are a new way to create
这是创建附加结构
additional structure and longer
运行时间更长的 UI
running UI and integration
以及集成测试的一种
tests.
新方式
There's a single API that lets
有一个单独的 API 可以
you group together sections of
把代码片段进行归类
code by wrapping them in
通过把它们包装在
closures passed to a new class
闭包中再传到新一类
XCTContext.
XCTContext 中来实现
Now here's part of the test
这是从 Warren 之前做的 Demo
report from Warren's demo
中得出的一个测试报告
earlier, which we didn't get a
我们还没来得及
chance to look at, but here it
去查看 但现在报告已经在
is now.
这里
And that test wasn't
这个测试并没有
particularly long or complex,
很长或很复杂
but you can see there's quite a
但大家可以看到这里面
lot going on here.
却有很多的内容
So, consider these four actions.
那么来思考一下这 4 个行动
Let's look at the code that
让我们来看看引导这些
caused them.
行动的代码
We have a query to find the
我们用一个查询来找到
view, we tap on it, type some
视图 我们可以点击视图 输入
text and interact with a few
一些文本并同几个按钮
buttons.
进行交互
This code makes a good logical
这个代码做了一个很好的逻辑
grouping, it's the code that
归类 这个代码
composes the any good coffee
汇集了所有优质咖啡厅
places message.
的信息
So, creating an XCTActivity for
所以 为这个代码创建一个
this code is very simple.
XCTActivity 是非常简单的
We simply wrap it in this run
我们只需把它包装进这个运行
activity call, we give it a nice
Activity 调用中 给它一个漂亮的
label because that's what we'll
标签 因为这是我们将在测试
show in the test report.
报告中所呈现的
Now let's look at how that
下面 让我们来看看这给
changes the test report.
测试报告带来了什么改变
We have the original four
我们原本的 4 个 Activity
activities now enclosed in this
现在被包在了这个
new activity compose coffee
由咖啡信息组成的新的
message and you can expand it
Activity 中 你仍然可以进行扩展
still and see the original, more
来看看初始的且更加
granular details underneath.
具体的细节
But for the high level first
但对于高层的首次
pass when you're looking at your
通过 当你在浏览自己的
test report things will now be
测试报告时 信息会变得
more concise and semantically
更加简洁并在语义上
meaningful.
更有意义
Using this API throughout your
在整个更长的运行测试
longer running tests and in
和在 Helper 方法中使用
helper methods will just make
这个 API 会让
the test reports much easier to
测试报告更易于
explore.
浏览
Now along with activities we've
除了 Activity 我们还
introduced something called
推出了叫做附件的
attachments.
新功能
For a long time now we've wanted
长久以来 我们一直希望
the ability to attach richer
能将更丰富的数据添加到
data to test reports.
测试报告中
The primary motivation is to
最主要的动机是为了
make it easier to triage
更容易地
failures with additional logs or
用额外的日志或其他数据来
other data that give insight
分流失败 这些数据能够在
into the conditions at the time
失败时提供关于条件的
of failure.
更多情况
In addition, this could be used
除此之外 这也可以被用来
to support various
支持各类
postprocessing workflows.
后处理工作流程
For example, sitting down with
比如同你的设计师
your designers and looking at
坐在一起来看看
screenshots together.
屏幕快照
Now attachment support any kind
现在附件可以通过便利 API
of binary data with convenience
支持任何类型的二进制
APIs for strings, property
数据 包括字符串
lists, codable objects, files
属性列表 可编码的对象 文件
and images.
和图像
Any of these types can easily be
这些类别中任何一类都可以
attached to your test so when
轻松添加到测试中 所以当
you look at the test report
你阅读测试报告时
there that data is.
数据就在那里了
And that brings us to the third
这就把我们带到了
edition in our group of
技术群组的第三大
technologies which are
内容 即
screenshots.
屏幕快照
Many of you have been asking us
多年来 在座的很多人都
over the years for an API to
要求我们提供一个可以
explicitly capture screenshots
按需显性捕捉
on demand.
屏幕快照的 API
Well we're happy to say that
我们很高兴地告诉大家
here it is, we hope you enjoy
现在我们做到了 希望大家会
it.
喜欢
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
This new XCUI screenshot
这个全新的可以提供
providing protocol is
屏幕快照的 XCUI 协议
implemented by both XCUIElement
是由 XCUIElement 以及
and a new class XCUIScreen.
新的 XCUIScreen 类来执行的
So, when you use an element and
所以 当你使用一个元素并
you capture a screenshot it'll
捕捉一张屏幕快照时
be clipped to just the frame of
会剪裁到只包含该元素的
that element.
图框
So, a button, you'll just see
如果元素是按钮 你就只会看到按钮
the button, a window you'll see
如果元素是窗口 你就会看到
the full window and so forth.
完整的窗口 以此类推
And if you use the screen API
如果你使用屏幕 API
you'll get the full screen
那么无论屏幕上
regardless of what application
显示了什么应用程序
or applications are present on
你都能看到
it.
全屏
Now with attachments and
现在有了附件和
screenshots, some of you may be
屏幕快照  在座一些人可能会
wondering how quickly will this
疑惑这得多快就
fill up my hard drive.
装满硬盘啦
Well the default policies for
对于附件以及在 UI
attachments and also for
测试过程中
screenshots that are captured
自动捕捉的
automatically during UI testing
屏幕快照的默认策略是
is that if your test passes we
如果测试通过了 那我们就
delete these for you.
帮你把这些删除
The assumption is in the common
这就假设了在一般情况下
case you don't need them, but if
根本不需要它们 但如果
your test fails they're present
测试失败了 它们才会显现
for you.
出来
Now you can override this policy
现在 你可以在 Scheme 中
in your scheme.
覆盖这个策略
In the same part of the UI where
在 UI 中存在本地化
that localization control exists
控制的相同部分
you can tell us whether you want
你可以告诉我们是否
screenshots captured at all
希望可以全自动捕捉
automatically and whether to
屏幕快照以及是否想要
delete these and attachments
把这些屏幕快照和附件删除
when tests succeed or not.
无论测试成功与否
There is also API on the
在附件类也有
attachment class that lets you
API 能够让你可以
on a per instance basis say keep
根据具体的实例来
this, don't keep that, and that
保留或者删除元素 及诸如
sort of thing.
此类的事
So, you'll see that in the next
接下来 大家可以在下一个
demo with attachments and
关于附件 Activity 和屏幕快照的 Demo 中
activities and screenshots in
来看看实际的
action.
场景
Please welcome Honza Dvorsky to
让我们欢迎 Honza Dvorsky
the stage.
上台
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Wil.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Wil
Good afternoon, my name is Honza
下午好 我叫 Honza
and today I'd like to show you
今天我将给大家展示
how we can organize your tests
我们如何使用 Activity 来
using activities, then how to
组织测试 以及如何
screenshot your UI with the new
利用新的屏幕快照 API 来
screenshot API, and finally how
给你的 UI 进行屏幕快照 最后还会看看
to attach arbitrary data with
如何将任意数据添加到
your tests.
测试中
So, we'll start by looking at
下面 我们首先来看看
the test report of Warren's
Warren 做的测试的
test.
测试报告
We can do that by
我们可以通过
Control-clicking on the test
按住 Control 键的同时单击
diamond and selecting
测试方块并选取
[inaudible] the report.
“Jump to Report（跳转到报告）”
When we disclose the test, we
当我们展开一项测试 我们
reveal the test to transcript.
便可以看到测试脚本
The test transcript contains all
测试脚本包含关于
the details about our test, but
测试的全部细节 但
when it gets longer it can be
当测试越久 就变得
difficult to navigate.
越难导航
In addition, what we see here
此外 我们在这儿看到的是
are these leveled steps like
类似这些标签和滑动的
these tabs and swipes, but it
分级步骤 这会
would help us to organize our
帮助我们在这些高层
test around these higher-level
任务周围组织测试
tasks like launch the app or
例如 启动应用程序或是
compose in send a new message.
编写发送一条新的信息
So, we'll use activities to do
我们用 Activity 所做的
just that.
正是这个
We'll jump back to the source
下面我们要回到源代码
and look for good candidates to
来寻找适合包装进第一项
wrap in our first activity.
Activity 的候选项
For example, this piece of code,
比如这一部分代码
compose and send a new message
编写和发送新的信息
takes care of that.
可以通过它实现
So, we wrap it in an activity by
那么 通过调用 XCTContext.runActivity
calling XCTContext.runActivity.
我们把它包装进一个 Activitiy
It takes two parameters, the
这需要两个参数
first is the name of the
第一个是 Activity 的名称
activity, compose and send a new
在我们的这个例子里就是
message in our case, and the
编写和发送新信息 第二个参数
second is the block, the block
是块
represents the scope of the
块代表了 Activity 的
activity.
范围
But we'll close it down here and
我们在这里加个大括号
that's it, that's all you need
就是这样 以上就是在一个
to do to wrap a piece of code in
Activity 中包装一段代码
an activity.
所须要做的全部
Now I'll sprinkle more
下面 我再给这个
activities around this test.
测试创建更多的 Activity
And we'll rerun the test to see
我们将重新运行这个测试来
how the test report changed.
看看测试报告将如何变动
You can see that I wrapped the
你可以看到我包装了
launching of the Reader app, the
readerApp 的启动
verification of the first
对首条信息的
message, the activation of the
验证 writerApp 的
Writer app, the composing and
激活以及新信息的
sending a new message and so on.
编写和发送等等
Now this is the same exact test
这是 Warren 之前编写
that Warren wrote here, but this
的那个文本
time the activities and the
但这一次这些 Activity 和我们
names we give them are getting
起的名字将作为
included in the output as
最高级成员
first-class citizens.
包含在输出中
So, we send our message, verify
所以 我们发送了信息
that it's the right one, and
验证了这是正确的信息
we're done.
我们就完成了
So, let's go back to the test
下面 让我们回到测试
report now.
报告上
When we reveal the transcript
当我们展开脚本时
now we can see it's much shorter
现在我们可以看到内容变得更短
and in addition, it better
并且除此之外 它更好地
describes what our test does.
描述了我们的测试所做的工作
It launches the Reader app,
它启动了 readerApp
verifies the first message,
验证了第一条信息
activates the Writer app,
激活了 writerApp、
composes and sends a new message
编写并发送了新的信息
and so on.
等等
But if you still need to know
但如果你还是需要了解
all the details about that
关于这个 Activity 的所有细节信息
activity all the sub activities
所有的子 Activity 都
are hidden one level deeper.
隐藏在更深的一层
So, activities are a great way
所以  Activity 是组织测试
to organize your tests.
的一种良好方式
Now let's switch gears a little
下面让我们来稍微换换
bit.
思路
Our designers that helped us
帮助我们设计应用程序的
with our app wanted to make sure
设计师们想确定
that our message cells here
我们的信息栏
follow their beautiful
完全遵守了他们
specification exactly.
的规范
So, what we'll do is write a UI
所以我们要做的就是编写一个
test which captures the visual
捕捉了应用程序视觉状态的
state of the app and then we'll
UI 测试 然后每个晚上
run this test every night on our
都在我们的机器人上运行这个
bots.
测试
This way, our designers can come
通过这种方式 我们的设计师可以
in and see what the app looks
在任何想来的时候来看看
like anytime they want.
应用程序的外观
So, this is a new class visual
所以这是新的类
validation tests.
VisualValidationTests
I already have the code to
我已经有了代码可以
launch the app in the state I
以我想要的方式启动
want it in and I also have this
应用程序 同时我还有
empty activity gather
空的 Activity 叫做 “Gather Screenshots（获取屏幕快照）”
screenshots and this is where
我们会把
we'll place our screenshots now.
我们的屏幕快照放在这里
We'll capture two screenshots,
我们会捕捉两个屏幕快照
the first of the full-screen of
第一个是应用程序的
the app and one of just the
全屏 而另一个则仅仅截取
first message cell.
第一个信息栏
So, to capture the full screen
那么 为了捕捉全屏
we use the new XCUIScreen API to
我们使用新的 XCUIScreen API 来
get a handle to the main screen.
控制主屏幕
Now as Wil mentioned, XCUIScreen
正如 Wil 所提到的那样 XCUIScreen
conforms to XCUI screenshot
遵循 XCUIScreenshotProviding 协议
providing so we can just simply
所以我们可以仅
ask it for a screenshot of
要求它自我
itself.
屏幕快照
Now we have the screenshot in
现在 我们的内存里有
memory and we somehow want to
屏幕快照 并且我们也想
persist it with our test and
在测试中继续保持
this is where attachments come
这时候附件就派上
in.
用场了
Attachments can hold any data
附件可以保存任何数据
and XCTAttachment provides
并且 XCTAttachment 为
convenience initializers for
便利初始化程序提供了
types like strings, files,
诸如字符串 文件
images and screenshots.
图像和屏幕快照等类别
So, we'll create a new
那么我们要创建一个新的
attachment to hold our
附件来保存
screenshots.
屏幕快照
Now as Wil mentioned, the
正如 Wil 提到的那样
attachments get deleted whenever
一旦测试通过了 屏幕快照
the test passes, it's a default
就被删除了 这个一个默认
behavior.
行为
But in our case here we want to
但在我们的例子中 我们希望
persist these attachments
无论测试结果如何
regardless of the test result.
都保留附件
We can do a separate attachment
我们可以创建一个单独的附件
by customizing its lifetime to
然后自定义附件的生命期让它
keep always.
始终保存
And finally, we add this
最后 我们把这个
attachment to an activity, we'll
附件加到 Activity 中 我们会把
add it to this activity that
它加到代表了
represents our gather
收集屏幕快照的
screenshots.
Activity 中
Now we captured the full screen,
现在我们捕捉了全屏
we also wanted to capture just
我们还想捕捉
the first message cell.
第一个信息栏
So, we first used the existing
那么首先 我们使用现有的
UI testing API to get an
UI 测试 API 来获取
XCUIElement for the cell.
信息栏的 XCUIElement
An XCUIElement also conforms to
XCUIElement 同样遵守
XCUI screenshot providing so we
XCUIScreenshotProviding 协议
can just follow the same steps
所以我们只须照着同样的
here.
步骤操作
We ask the cell for a screenshot
我们命令信息栏对自身进行
of itself, we create an
屏幕快照 我们为它创建
attachment for it, customize its
一个附件 自定义它的
lifetime and add the attachment
生命期并将附件添加到
to the activity.
Activity 中
So, let's run the test now and
那么现在 让我们来运行测试
see what we get.
看看会出现什么
This is a simple test that just
这是一个简单的测试 只需要
launches our app and captures
启动应用程序 捕捉
the two screenshots, adds those
两个屏幕快照 把这两个屏幕快照
two screenshots as attachments
作为附件添加
and finishes.
就完成了
That's it.
就是这样
So, we go to the test report.
下面再来看看测试报告
Now when we reveal the test we
当我们展开测试时 我们
see our gather screenshots
看到了获取屏幕快照的
activity and it contains our two
Activity 它含有两个
attachments and [inaudible]
附加以及
activity.
子 Activity
So, this is the attachment that
那么这是代表了第一个
represents the first main screen
主屏幕屏幕快照的附件
screenshot and this represents
而这个代表了
the screenshot of just the
只有信息栏的
message cell.
屏幕快照
We could use this QuickLook icon
我们可以使用快速预览图标
here to get a preview window for
来获取预览窗口
it, but in fact I want to use
但实际上 我想使用
this the Assistant Editor to do
这个“Assistant Editor（助理编辑器）”来
that.
实现
So, we just select the right
我们只需选取正确的
screenshot and this is our
屏幕快照 这就是我们的
full-screen screenshot and this
全屏屏幕快照 这个是
is the screenshot of just the
只有第一个信息栏的
first message cell.
屏幕快照
So, now you can see how super
这样你就可以看到捕捉
easy it is to capture, oh
是多么的简单容易了
thanks.
对吧
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Now you can see how easy it is
现在你可以看到通过这个
to really capture any screen or
新的屏幕快照 API 来真正捕捉
element you have in your app
应用程序中的任何屏幕
with the new screenshot API and
或元素并且利用新的附件 API
attach it to the test with the
来把屏幕快照添加到测试中
new attachments API.
是多么容易了
I really hope you give it a try.
我真心希望大家都能试一试
Okay and with that I would like
好了 那下面我再有请
to invite Wil back to wrap
Wil 回到台上
things up for us.
来进行总结
Wil.
有请 Wil
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Honza, that is pretty
谢谢你 Honza 简直
awesome stuff, you can see just
太精彩了 大家可以看到
how easy activities make it to
Activity 在改进测试架构
improve the test structure and
方面是多么容易
capturing rich data with
使用附件来捕捉
attachments will make fixing
丰富的数据将使修复测试失败
your test failures simpler than
变得前所未有的容易
ever and screenshots, I mean who
还有屏幕快照 难道还有人
doesn't love screenshots.
不喜欢屏幕快照吗
Activities, attachments and
这就是 Activity  附件和
screenshots it's a great new set
屏幕快照 这是大家在测试中
of technologies for use in your
可以使用的一全新的领先
tests.
技术
So, we started off with what's
所以 今天我们以测试
new in testing and as you can
新发现作为开头 你也可以看出来
see, quite a lot.
内容丰富多样
We have many new APIs for you to
我们有很多新的 API 供大家
use and we didn't even touch on
使用 今天甚至没来得及将它们
all of them here today.
逐个介绍
So, we have lots of new APIs and
我们有很多新的 API
we have the new workflow and
我们也有新的工作流以及
continuous integration features
Xcode 中的持续集成功能
in Xcode, Xcodebuild and Xcode
还有 xcodebuild 命令和 Xcode Server
Server and we have those great
我们还
performance improvements in UI
极大提升了 UI 测试的
testing.
性能
So, thanks for coming today.
最后 感谢大家到场
The session, page session of
通过上方的链接 可以找到
that link above has all the
关于本次会议的所有
related resources and
相关资料和
documentation, everything you're
文件 你想看的全部
looking for.
都在这里
And of course, we have lots of
当然 我们在过去举办了
sessions in the past and one
很多场会议
tomorrow that I encourage you to
明天还有一场希望大家可以
check out.
参加
Also, the previous years'
前几年的会议中
sessions have some really great
确实有一些很有用的
information about other parts of
信息是关于 Xcode 测试的
testing in Xcode that we didn't
其他方面 都是我们在今天
really take a close look at
没能仔细探讨的
today.
内容
Thanks.
感谢大家